Mohamed Omar Farook

Email:mohamedomarfarookvm@gmail.com

Phone: +91 7824001944

Current Job: Front End Developer at Tata Consultancy Services.

Career Objective

Innovative, creative and a proven team player with 4+ years of experience in designing, developing and managing complex web and mobile applications and programs for various clients. I hope to share my skills, expertise and experience with your team and valuable clients.

Strengths

- ProficientinHTML5,CSS3,Javascript,JQuery,LESS,SASS, Bootstrap
- Experience in using Front End Frameworks Angular, React, React Native, Redux, Nextjs
- Keen understanding of responsive designprinciples
- Experienced in using Functional, Unit testing methods and Code Review to deliver high quality, fit for purpose software with emphasis on testability and maintainability.
- Strong experience of working in agile teams and using Continuous Delivery to get quick feedback and improve constantly
- Possess a knack of teamwork and comfortable working cross functional

Work Experience

Lead Front End Developer (Aug 2018 - Present) Client: MYER - Australia

The imperative part is to deal with the development of Online e-commerce web application and iOS native in-store application (used for warehouse fulfilment). As part of online changes, we implemented shopping path features for better customer journey and promotions during Christmas and New year sales. And for in-store application, We have developed native iOS application for iPod device which performs pick-up and packing of online orders swiftly.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Designs, develops and relaunches responsive e-commerce sites of the client
- Improved Site Performance by implementing asynchronous content rendering (CMS) by using custom reusable components in Reactis.
- Executes full-stack website launches specializing in front-end features, browser manipulation, and cross-browser compatibility
- Managed multiple projects with a team of backend engineers and QA from planning to website launch.
- Oversees creation and maintenance of front-end standard documents

Front End Developer (Jul 2017 – Jul 2018) Client: BJ's – USA

The paramount objective is to develop an application for both Business-to-Consumer and Business-to-Business as a part of single project. The Business-to-Consumer comprises of order creation (Browsing, placing and tracking the order) and Business-to-Business which is specially designed for wholesaler/Retailer. Implemented SSR and state transfer to improve the performance of an application and providing seo feature.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Designed and Developed entire shopping path of Business to business application for the client.
- Integrated layout architecture in angular framework for home and PDP page.
- Implemented SSR and StateTransfer in our application to support SEO and to improve the performance of the application.
- Integrated third party libraries like Certona, Criteo in our application for Recommended products.
- Interpreted and executed designs correctly as requested by client.

Front End Developer (Nov 2015–Jun2017) Client: DSG – USA

The prime scope is to build a comprehensive responsive frontend part of ecommerce application which includes adding pertinent promotions, shopping path, purchase path, Buy online and pick up in store (BOPIS) feature. This provides an additional option for customers to place online orders as well.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Designs, develops and relaunches responsive B2C e-commerce sites of the client
- Developed and implemented effective solutions that are integrated to company's information technology standard
- Coordinated with team of UX designers to create new Web Content Management system
- Actively participates and engages the Software Support team in resolving production issues.
- Converted Photoshop layouts to web pages using HTML, CSS, Flex and bootstrap
- Presented web-site mock-ups to clients to give them better visual of the end product and to ensure that all parameters were met.
- Worked closely with the design team and project managers and ensured projects are delivered in a timely manner

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering (2011-15) Anna University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu.